# Dhruv Gajjar

(847) 890-1847 dgajjar2@illinois.edu

**SUMMARY** 

Portfolio Website: <a href="https://www.dhruvgajjar.com">https://www.dhruvgajjar.com</a>
Social: <a href="https://www.dhruvgajjar.com/in/dhruvgajjar">www.linkedin.com/in/dhruvgajjar</a>

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Engineering Physics student who is a quick learner, highly analytical, and easily adaptable. Experienced in data analysis/automation, database structure, and construction and engineering in the energy distribution industry. Brought on process improvement changes in data collection, retention, and reporting at WEC Energy Group by using the ability to incorporate disparate approaches and subjects when solving problems

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## WEC Energy Group/Peoples Gas (Chicago, IL) Performance Engineering Student Intern

May 2018 - Aug 2018

- Developed a demo database using Microsoft SQL Server to introduce the benefits of utilizing databases within the Engineering Department rather than pulling data from Microsoft Sharepoint, which resulted in approval from the department manager to begin the initial steps of designing a plan of execution and cleaning the necessary data sources to ensure data integrity
- Designed VBA programs to rapidly pull and consolidate data from over 300 sources in multiple directories that assisted in cost analysis for future consultant contract negotiations and budget forecasting based on current spending
- Assumed a data analyst role; started the process of automating and standardizing multiple procedures and data sources in the Engineering and Contracts department leading to better record keeping for easier future analysis
- Analyzed proposed plans submitted by other utilities to the City of Chicago's Office of Underground Coordination to determine possible conflicts with the company's existing gas mains and facilities
- WEC Energy Group/Peoples Gas (Chicago, IL)
   Distribution Engineering Student Intern

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- Designed and implemented an automated quality assurance VBA program for job-site measurements, which is still currently utilized as a tool by the current team of engineers and saved hours of manual data entry
- Performed 10 field audits for upcoming construction projects to ensure compliance with Chicago's regulatory rules
- o Modeled gas flow simulations for proposed gas mains to determine if construction would be non-intrusive to the area
- o Executed pipeline retirement changes on the company's ESRI GIS mapping software once new pipe was installed

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

Expected Graduation: Dec 2018

 B.S. in Engineering Physics; Specialization in Mechanical Engineering GPA: 3.37/4.00

Relevant Courses: Intro to Computer Science; Intro to Data Science; Intro to Databases; Applied Linear Algebra

#### **PROJECTS**

## Mass Produced Electro-Mechanical Invention/Innovation; Course Name: Computer Aided Design

- Collaborated with a team to create a product that solves a commonly faced problem. Designed an easy-to-use clothing iron attached to an ironing board which is ideal for tight spaces and frequent travelers. Deliverables: 3D CAD models, engineering drawings, and a cost analysis of materials and manufacturing processes used
- Projectile Launcher Simulation and Design; Course Name: Introduction to Dynamics
- Contributed Engineering Physics background to the testing, experimentation, and simulation of the projectile and environment conditions. Deliverables: a report of the simulation and experiment and a working, testable prototype

### **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE, EXTRACURRICULARS, & AWARDS**

#### Alpha Phi Omega Service Fraternity Events

Jan 2017 - Present

Held four high-level leadership positions within the fraternity and completed 100+ hours of community service

College-Level Math and Physics Tutor

Aug 2014 - May 2016

Illinois Student Assistance Commission Scholar

Jun 2015 Jun 2015

Prairie State Achievement Award: Reading, Mathematics, and Science

## **SKILLS & CERTIFICATIONS**

- **Software:** Autodesk Inventor, Microsoft Access, Microsoft SQL Server, Synergi Gas, Creo Parametric 3.0, WMIS, ESRI, ArcGIS, Git, and high-level proficiency in Microsoft Excel, Word, and Powerpoint
- Programming Languages: Visual Basic/VBA, Python, MATLAB, HTML, CSS, Javascript, and SQL
- Languages: English (Native Proficiency), Hindi (Intermediate)
- Certifications: Advanced Google Analytics; GTI Pipeline Safety Regulatory Compliance Course